#### Contact

raghuaditya.chavali@gmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/aditya-kiran (LinkedIn) github.com/Aditya-kiran (Other)

## Top Skills

Deep Learning
Probabilistic Models
Machine Learning Algorithms

## Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Tamil (Limited Working)

### Honors-Awards

Best Poster Award (Robotics Category)

#### **Publications**

Inferring Distribution of Parameterized Controller for Efficient Sampling-Based Locomotion of Underactuated Robots

Effect of process parameters on the conventional high speed drilling of glass

# Raghu Aditya C.

Machine Learning Enthusiast | Data Scientist at Microsoft Irvine, California

# Summary

I am a machine learning enthusiast and data scientist with over 2 years of experience building, training and optimizing neural network architectures to solve challenging problems using, but not limited to, tensorflow, pyrotch and pyspark. My graduate research in using Artificial Intelligence for legged robot locomotion led to a first author publication in the American Control Conference 2019. My individuality is reflected in my ability to integrate key aspects from various domains of my CMU graduate coursework into my work. I am currently working as a data scientist at Microsoft in the Cloud and Al division. I am looking to connect with other enthusiasts in this field to discuss research papers and undertake personal projects to help augment each other's skillset in this domain.

# Experience

Microsoft
Data Scientist
March 2020 - Present (1 month)
United States

Obsidian Security
Machine learning/Data scientist Intern
July 2019 - January 2020 (7 months)
Newport beach, California, United States

As a Machine Learning/Data Scientist:

- Identified critical insights in cloud service recommendation system to improve security posture and identity protection by analyzing raw API data, performing k-means clustering and logistic regression on Administrative Roles & Permissions.
- Built an algorithm to rank Administrative roles based on the sensitivity of their permissions using PostgreSQL, Databricks, pyspark and dynamic programming.

- Identified, analyzed and deployed key improvements to data extractors to label Internal, External, Licensed and Unlicensed Users across cloud services. Final results were pushed to the live Obsidian product.
- Designed data structures in python to map the Application API endpoints to the OAuth permission scopes.

Carnegie Mellon University
Research Assistant
May 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 1 month)
United States

As a research assistant at the Biorobotics Lab under Prof Matthew Travers, I:

- Researched and implemented a novel approach using Probabilistic Graphical Models to reduce sampling space and computation time in locomotion planning for highly-articulated robots.
- Developed Reinforcement Learning Algorithms & Evolutionary Algorithm to collect training data for an underactuated hexapod robot with 18 DOF using Gazebo simulations, Ros control, and CUDA optimizations.
- Designed an automated framework capable of levying offline training data for inferring online behaviour parameters.
- Published as first author in the American Control Conference, July 12, 2019. (refer to publication section for citation).
- Won the Best Poster Award in the 'Robotics' category at the CMU Annual Graduate Research Symposium 2019.

Indian Institute Of Chemical Technology Junior Research Fellow May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Researched and built a custom centrifuge machine to improve oil extraction efficiency in peanuts

# Education

Carnegie Mellon University

Master's degree, Research: Artificial Intelligence for Legged robot locomotion · (2017 - 2019)

College of Engineering, Guindy
Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering (2013 - 2017)